# XIAOYU CHEN / MAVIS

Phone: (61)- 0450-520-805 E-mail: <a href="mailto:mavischen916@gmail.com">mavischen916@gmail.com</a>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/xychenxy">https://github.com/xychenxy</a> Website: <a href="https://developer-mavis.netlify.app">https://developer-mavis.netlify.app</a>

## **ABOUT ME**

I have been working in the Australia ICT environment for more than *two years* and gained commercial experience. I primarily focus on JavaScript/ES6, HTML5 and CSS3, and I develop websites/desktop app with a number of frameworks such as React, Node.js, Electron. I have experience on integrating API, such as UBER API, Australia Post API and Shopify StoreFront API.

# **KEY SKILLS**

- Front-end: React.js/Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS3, Sass/Less, Bootstrap, Ant Design, Material-UI, Electron (Desktop apps), Gatsby/React, GraphQL, Webpack
- Back-end: Node.js/Express, NPM, Yarn, Java, Python
- Database: NoSQL/MongoDB, MySQL
- API: Uber API, Australia Post API, Shopify StoreFront API, Couriers Please API, Google API, JSON, RESTful API, Axios, Postman
- Testing: Jest, Mocha
- Cloud: AWS EC2, Route53, CloudFront, S3, Nginx, CI/CD
- Version Control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### JavaScript developer

Palette | Melbourne | 8/2020 - 5/2021 | https://tintpaint.com.au

I am the only one developer to develop and maintain the Warehouse System and Analyst Dashboard. *Warehouse System* is a desktop app which is created by Electron/React. It is processing eCommerce orders, tinting paint, tracking stock levels, integrating with dispatch partners. *Analyst Board* is a web app which is created by React. It is aiming to provide decision makers with analytics data.

# Warehouse System

- Tech stack includes React/Redux, Node, Electron, TypeScript, Ant-Design, MongoDB, AWS, Bitbucket, Nginx, PM2, Figma, Webpack, NPM
- Processing eCommerce orders via Shopify StoreFront API
- Printing selected packing lists
- Tracking stock levels via Dear Inventory System API
- Tinting customized colour paints
- Showing all delivery fees, expected delivery days and delivery methods via Uber, Australia Post, Couriers Please API

• Printing shipping labels automatically after booking delivery via Python script

#### Analyst Dashboard

- Creating and Optimizing analytics data for decision *maker via running algorithms*
- Providing search, date range, sort, add comment *functions* in dashboard
- Tracking all orders' delivery status via API
- Generating sales reports and auto sending everyday via AWS endpoints
- User management, such as add, delete
- Caching endpoints requests and Database queries for better performance

Key words: React/Redux, Electron, TypeScript, Node, AWS, API Integration

## Front-end developer

Foodifox | Melbourne | 12/2020 - Current | https://foodifox.com/

I am the only one developer to develop and maintain the Foodifox Website. Foodifox Website is a web app which is created by React, Gatsby and GraghQL. It is a pure HTML, CSS application without any UI framework.

- Showing company's products and culture
- Customers can enquire via EmailJS
- Completing 8 pages

Key words: Gatsby/React/GraghQL, HTML, CSS3, Adobe XD, Netlify, GoDaddy and GitHub

#### Web developer

RMIT University | 10/2019 – 12/2019 | https://app.openingthedoors.org.au/

I am the web developer to create front end pages and maintain the whole project. Opening the Door Foundation is a web app which is created by Symfony. It is aiming to support the extra costs associated with schooling for Aboriginal students around Victoria.

- Showing application form
- Tracking all the applications
- Approval rules

Key words: Symfony/PHP, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, AWS, Agile

### Web developer

AlU Group | Melbourne | 1/2019 - 4/2019 | https://www.aiugroup.com.au/

- Creating 10 pages for investors to track their projects and expenditure
- The project was developed by WordPress, MySQL, Bootstrap, jQuery and deployed in AWS

## **EDUCATION**

#### RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia

3/2018-12/2019

Major: Master of Information Technology

• WAM: 76/100